Hello everyone, welcome to my invest
buddy. Today we will discuss about a
health insurance plan by ICI Lombard.
ICI as a group needs no introduction. So
let's get straight into the plan. So the
name of this plan is elevate. If we talk
about the features of this plan, it
covers hospitalization up to some
assured. By default, it provides a
single private AC room. But there's a
rider which if you choose it, you can
take any room of your choice.
Daycare procedures are covered. Pre and
post hospitalization is standard which
is there in all the policies.
Prehospization is 90 days and post
hospitalization is 180 days. Donor
expenses are covered. Doicillary
hospitalization is covered. The concept
of domicillary hospitalization arises in
situations where patient is in a
critical condition. They cannot be taken
to to an hospital. So if a patient needs
at least 3 day of domicillary
hospitalization, it will be covered in
the policy. IU treatments are covered.
Domestic road ambulance is covered.
There's a benefit called reset benefit.
What this means is uh suppose you have a
10 lakh insurance policy and you made a
claim during a policy year. During the
same year, you can make another claim of
10 lakh. So your 10 lakhs on my short is
repled unlimited number of times.
There's a loyalty bonus of 20% each year
up to a maximum of 100%. So if you have
a 10 lakh policy and you don't make any
claims in a policy year, next year your
summit short will become 12 lakh. It
will keep on increasing by 22 lakh which
is 20% of 10 lakh up to 20 lakhs. These
are the basic features. Apart from it,
this policy provides a lots of add-ons
which you can choose based on your
needs. So the very first add-on is
worldwide cover. If you choose this
rider, you can get your treatment
anywhere across the world. There's an
option for NRI to get a 25% discount on
the insurance premium. Infinite care is
another rider. Now, what it does is uh
during entire policy lifetime, company
gives you an option, you can make one
claim of infinite amount. Suppose your
insurance policy is of 10 lakh, you can
make a claim of any amount. But it is
applicable only once during entire
policy lifetime. Another important
feature is 2 hours hospitalization.
What does it mean is it will cover
medical expenses if there's an
hospitalization for more than 2 hours.
Power booster. The benefit of this rider
is your sum assured will keep on
increasing 100% like every year. So if
you have a 10 lakh insurance policy,
next year your uh some assured will
become 20 lakh, 30 lakh. it will keep on
increasing whether you make or do not
make a claim. Another rider is jump
start. So if someone is having a
preexisting disease like ama, diabetes,
hypertension, cholesterol and obesity
and if they choose this rider, these
five pre-existing diseases will get
covered from the 31st day of the policy
issuance. It covers non-payable items
like gloves, cotton, syringes, masks,
etc. Inflation protector is another
rider which is not very necessary. The
policy also mentions maternity benefit
but the cost of this rider is very high.
So it does not make sense to opt this
rider in this policy. By default the
health checkup option is not available
in the policy. If you want this option
you can take health checkup rider. There
is another rider bequit rider which
covers OPD plans. But just like
maternity, the cost benefit for this
bequit rider does not make it sense to
choose this rider. There's a room
modifier add-on which you must choose.
Uh so by default this policy has a
single private AC room room. If you
choose this rider, you can take any room
of your choice. So this rider should be
chosen. There's a personal accident and
critical illness rider which you can
choose based on your need. If you have
to summarize the features of ICIC
elevate health insurance, what it covers
is it cover there's no co-ayment. There
is no limits on room if you choose a
room modifier add-on. There is no
disease by sum limit. It covers daycare
treatments. It provides unlimited
restoration of some assured.
There's a rider which you can choose to
cover for consumables. PD waiting period
is the standard. all the good health
insurance companies IU treatments is
covered in this policy. Health checkup
is another rider which you can choose.
So based on our checklist this IC
credential elevates covers all the
essential things
and the good part about this is the
discounts uh ICIC elevate provide credit
score discount if your credit score is
greater than 750 you can get up to 15%
discount on the premiums. So this is
about the features of ICICI elate health
insurance plan. If you're looking for a
good health insurance plan for your
family, consult us. We will help you
find the best insurance plan suitable
for your needs. Thank you.